RODRIGO ARENAS CATALÁN



PERSONAL DETAILS

Starowiślna 17/8, 31-038 Kraków rodarecat@gmail.com, +48511343557 Polish Residence and Work Permit

PROFILE

Sales Professional with over 9 years of B2B sales experience in Biotechnology and Agribusiness products and services in Latin America, Asia, and Europe. I specialize in market research, creating Go-To-Market strategies, and active client acquisition during international events. I'm a very positive and strongly determined person with a passion for sales, seeking to further develop my skills and expertise in sales management. My interpersonal skills and advanced knowledge of foreign languages have allowed me to successfully position my company's products in the demanding Japanese and European markets.

EMPLOYMENT

Chief Sales Manager Apr 2023 - Present

Crop Production Robotics, Poland & Germany

- Applied and was awarded with his team 3 German fundings: 1) EXIST, 2) ESA-BIC and 3) Ideenwettbewerb Bioökonomie 2023.
- Positioned the company's services into the German market, through market research, presentations, and networking. In less than four months, received over 20 Lols with German farmers for early-bird sales.
- Working with our internal Product manager in order to meet prospect and client expectations.
- Manage team-work flow in Next Cloud, and Kanban board.
- Client management using the Dolibarr platform.

Payments Specialist with Japanese

Mar 2019 - Jun 2020

Revolut, Poland

- In charge of English and Japanese-speaking customers for transfer-related issues.
- Collaborating with other teams via email and SQL queries.
- Establish, maintain, and develop partner and client relationships on an international level.

Sales Manager for Asia and Europe

Jun 2015 - Jan 2019

Atacama Bio Natural Products, Chile & Poland

- Japanese market researcher.
- Identify and qualify new leads, to convert them into long-term partners.
- Presenter of the company's product "Natural Astaxanthin" at different international events such as "HI Europe", "Aqua" and "HI Japan" 2016, 2017, 2018 in the Japanese language.
- Increased the company's Sales and cooperation with Japanese, Chinese, and Taiwanese top companies by an average of 85% as compared to the previous year.

Lecturer for Law school students

Jan 2015 - Jan 2016

Universidad Católica del Norte & Universidad Católica del Norte, Chile [https://www.ucn.cl/][https://www.ust.cl/sedes/la-serena/]

I consent to the processing of my personal data for the purpose of recruitment for the position to which I am applying.

This resume is made with CVwizard.com.

• Lecturer for three elective subjects for Law faculty students: 1) "Introduction to Asian Studies", 2) "
Fundamentals of Asian Law" and 3) "International Trade". For two years, was chosen as the most popular elective subject, always reaching the maximum number of students.

Sales and Accountant Manager Assistant

Jan 2010 - Jan 2011

Marubeni, Chile

- Assisted the Account Manager in collecting information for surveys, researching new equipment, performing new investments, etc.
- Functions concerning the accountability and financial results of the imports and exports of the company.
- Keeping direct communication with Marubeni Tokyo mainly through emails in Japanese and with Marubeni New York in both English and Japanese.
- In charge of the General Manager's written translations as well as Real-time translations for conferences with the press.

SKILLS

| Interpersonal Skills | Networking |
|----------------------|--------------------|
| Ms Office | Kanban board |
| Dolibarr ERP CRM | JIRA, Excel, Slack |
| HTML & CSS | Photoshop |
| Joomla & WordPress | Github |
| SQL queries | Javascript |
| Agile Scrum | |

EDUCATION

Master in International Relations

Feb 2013 - Dec 2014

University of Melbourne

2-year Full-time studies in English. Graduated with Second Class Honours (H2B). The study programme focused on the Asia-Pacific area.

Bachelor in Laws Apr 2005 - Feb 2010

Hokkaido University

5-years Full-time studies in Japanese. Graduated with Second Class Honours (良 – Good). Specialization in International Relations

Research Project in Agroecology

Oct 2018 - Feb 2023

Jagiellonian University

Initially in English but later fully in Polish language. Awarded ERASMUS but refused it to take a Sales role at Crop Robotics.

I consent to the processing of my personal data for the purpose of recruitment for the position to which I am applying.

This resume is made with CVwizard.com.

LANGUAGES

| Spanish | English |
|------------|---------|
| Japanese | Polish |
| Portuguese | German |

ACHIEVEMENTS

"Bio Economy" Funding [Ideenwettbewerb Bioökonomie 2023]

Sep 2023 [https://mlr.baden-wuerttemberg.de/de/unsere-themen/biooekonomie-und-innovation/ideenwettbewerb-biooekonomie/ideenwettbewerb-biooekonomie-2023]
Our startup Crop Robotics was awarded EUR 10.000, an interview and a promotional video.

"EXIST" Funding [University-Based Business Start-Ups – German Federal Ministry of Economic Affairs and Climate Action]

Apr 2023 [https://www.exist.de/EXIST/Navigation/EN/Home/home.html]

Awarded this prestigious funding and assumed the role of Chief Sales Manager at our startup Crop Robotics.

"ESA-BIC" Funding [Business Incubation Center from Baden-Wüttenberg]

Oct 2022 [https://www.esa-bic-bw.de/]

Our startup Crop Robotics was awarded EUR 60.000 but had to refuse them due to the requirement to register the company, which would have disqualified us for other fundings.

"Erasmus" Scholarship [For Studies at the Radboud University]

Oct 2022 [https://erasmus.uj.edu.pl/en_GB]

Awarded but had to refuse it in order to take the Sales role at Crop Robotics.

"Becas Chile" Scholarship [Master in International Relations]

Dec 2012 [https://www.chileatiende.gob.cl/fichas/74911-beca-de-magister-en-el-extranjero-becas-chile] Top-ten in the list of selected recipients. Graduated with Second Class Honours (H2B) from the University of Melbourne

"Monbukagakusho" Scholarship for Undergraduate Studies [Bachelor in Laws]

Mar 2005 [https://www.global.hokudai.ac.jp/]

Only Chilean scholarship recipient for the 2004-2005 period. Best result in admission exams in 3 years.

QUALITIES

| - Francisco | ■ Devesion sets |
|--------------|-----------------|
| ■ Energetic | ■ Passionate |
| Creative | ■ Determined |
| Consistent | ■ Hard-working |
| ■ Systematic | ■ Reliable |

I consent to the processing of my personal data for the purpose of recruitment for the position to which I am applying.

This resume is made with CVwizard.com.